[
    {
        "question": "What is the applied voltage for a series RLC circuit when IT = 3 mA, VL = 30 V, VC = 18 V, and R = 1000 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "3.00 V",
        "b": "12.37 V",
        "c": "34.98 V",
        "d": "48.00 ",
        "answer": "12.37 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1013_1.gifWhat is the bandwidth of the circuit?\r\n",
        "a": "31.8 Hz",
        "b": "32.3 Hz",
        "c": "142 Hz",
        "d": "7.2 kHz",
        "answer": "31.8 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a parallel RLC circuit, which value may always be used as a vector reference?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "current",
        "b": "reactance",
        "c": "resistance",
        "d": "voltage",
        "answer": "voltage"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much current will flow in a 100 Hz series RLC circuit if VS = 20 V, RT = 66 ohms, and XT = 47 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1.05 A",
        "b": "303 mA",
        "c": "247 mA",
        "d": "107 mA",
        "answer": "247 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Q (Quality factor) of a series circuit that resonates at 6 kHz, has equal reactance of 4 kilo-ohms each, and a resistor value of 50 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0.001",
        "b": "50",
        "c": "80",
        "d": "4.0",
        "answer": "80"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the range between f1 and f2 of an RLC circuit that resonates at 150 kHz and has a Q of 30?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz",
        "b": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz",
        "c": "4500 kHz to 295.5 kHz",
        "d": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz",
        "answer": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1012_1.gifWhat is the quality factor?\r\n",
        "a": "999",
        "b": "223",
        "c": "2.2",
        "d": "0.99",
        "answer": "2.2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect will a parallel tank have upon final filter current?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "very little",
        "b": "The bandpass frequencies will change.",
        "c": "The frequency cutoff will change.",
        "d": "The impedance will block output.",
        "answer": "very little"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1008_1.gifWhat is the total current?\r\n",
        "a": "56.6 mA",
        "b": "141 mA",
        "c": "191 mA",
        "d": "244 mA",
        "answer": "141 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a parallel circuit resonates it is said to:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "flywheel",
        "b": "oscillate",
        "c": "both of the above",
        "d": "none of the above",
        "answer": "both of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1008.gifWhat is the resonant frequency in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "11.6 Hz",
        "b": "275.8 Hz",
        "c": "1.5 kHz",
        "d": "3.2 kHz",
        "answer": "3.2 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "Series RLC voltage or impedance totals must be calculated by:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "subtracting the values",
        "b": "graphing the angles",
        "c": "adding vectors",
        "d": "multiplying the values",
        "answer": "adding vectors"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1006_1.gifWhat is the total current?\r\n",
        "a": "15.6 mA",
        "b": "17.8 mA",
        "c": "21.9 mA",
        "d": "26.0 mA",
        "answer": "15.6 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "When XC = XL the circuit:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "draws maximum current",
        "b": "applied voltage is zero",
        "c": "is at resonance",
        "d": "draws minimum current",
        "answer": "is at resonance"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much current will flow in a series RLC circuit when VT = 100 V, XL = 160 ohm, XC = 80 ohm, and R = 60 ohm?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1 A",
        "b": "1 mA",
        "c": "6.28 A",
        "d": "10 A",
        "answer": "1 A"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a full band of frequencies is allowed to pass through a filter circuit to the output, the resonant circuit is called a:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "low-pass filter",
        "b": "high-pass filter",
        "c": "band-stop filter",
        "d": "bandpass filter",
        "answer": "bandpass filter"
    },
    {
        "question": "At resonance, the term bandwidth includes all frequencies that allow what percentage of maximum current to flow?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "50",
        "b": "62.3",
        "c": "70.7",
        "d": "95.3",
        "answer": "70.7"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1002.gifWhat is the voltage across the capacitor in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "6.8 V",
        "b": "11.9 V",
        "c": "16.1 V",
        "d": "22.9 V",
        "answer": "22.9 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1006.gifWhat is the impedance of the circuit in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1.05 k ohm",
        "b": "1.33 k ohm",
        "c": "2.19 k ohm",
        "d": "3.39 k ohm",
        "answer": "1.05 k ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a series RLC circuit the current can be found using:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "IT = VR\/R",
        "b": "IT = VS\/Z",
        "c": "both of the above",
        "d": "none of the above",
        "answer": "both of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the true power consumed in a 30 V series RLC circuit if Z = 20 ohms and R = 10 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "15.0 watts",
        "b": "22.5 watts",
        "c": "30.0 watts",
        "d": "45.0 watts",
        "answer": "22.5 watts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the current phase angle for a parallel RLC circuit when IL = 15.3 A, IC = 0.43 A, and IR = 3.5 A?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "76.7 degrees",
        "b": "\u20134.25 degrees",
        "c": "88.8 degrees",
        "d": "\u201376.7 degrees",
        "answer": "\u201376.7 degrees"
    },
    {
        "question": "At any resonant frequency, what voltage is measured across the two series reactive components?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "applied",
        "b": "reactive",
        "c": "zero",
        "d": "inductive and capacitive",
        "answer": "zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1011_1.gifWhat is the resonance frequency?\r\n",
        "a": "31.8 Hz",
        "b": "71 Hz",
        "c": "7.1 kHz",
        "d": "31.8 kHz",
        "answer": "71 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the range between f1 and f2 of an RLC circuit that resonates at 150 kHz and has a Q of 30?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz",
        "b": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz",
        "c": "4500 kHz to 295.5 kHz",
        "d": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz",
        "answer": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1004.gifWhat is the bandwidth in the given circuit. If the winding resistance of the coil is 12 omega.gif?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "6.4 kHz",
        "b": "47.2 kHz",
        "c": "53.7 kHz",
        "d": "60.2 kHz",
        "answer": "6.4 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "At any resonant frequency, what net voltage is measured across the two series reactive components?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Applied voltage",
        "b": "Reactive voltage",
        "c": "Zero voltage",
        "d": "VL + VC voltage",
        "answer": "Zero voltage"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the bandwidth of a filter increases:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Q decreases",
        "b": "the roll-off rate increases",
        "c": "the half-power frequency decreases",
        "d": "the center frequency decreases",
        "answer": "Q decreases"
    },
    {
        "question": "Series RLC impedance or voltage totals must always be calculated by\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "adding values vectorially",
        "b": "graphing the angles",
        "c": "multiplying the values",
        "d": "subtracting the values",
        "answer": "adding values vectorially"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1006.gifWhat is the current through the capacitor in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "3.5 mA",
        "b": "5.5 mA",
        "c": "9 mA",
        "d": "11.4 mA",
        "answer": "3.5 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total impedance of a 60 Hz series RLC circuit when XL = 7.5 ohms, XC = 265.3 ohms, and R = 33 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "257.8 ohms",
        "b": "259.9 ohms",
        "c": "290.8 ohms",
        "d": "1989.75 ohms",
        "answer": "259.9 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1008.gifWhat is the total current for the nonideal circuit in the given circuit. If it is at resonance?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0 A",
        "b": "284 u A",
        "c": "3.3 mA",
        "d": "38.5 mA",
        "answer": "284 u A"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the high cutoff frequency for an RLC circuit that resonates at 2000 Hz and has a bandwidth of 250 Hz?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "2125 Hz",
        "b": "2250 Hz",
        "c": "1750 Hz",
        "d": "8.0 Hz",
        "answer": "2125 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "Current in a series RLC circuit may always be used as:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a leading vector",
        "b": "a reference",
        "c": "an angle",
        "d": "a lagging vector",
        "answer": "a reference"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1005_1.gifWhat is the impedance of the circuit?\r\n",
        "a": "12.2 k ohm",
        "b": "14.5 k ohm",
        "c": "17.8 k ohm",
        "d": "20.3 k ohm",
        "answer": "20.3 k ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1004.gifWhat is the resonant frequency in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "6.5 kHz",
        "b": "53.7 kHz",
        "c": "107.4 kHz",
        "d": "18.1 MHz",
        "answer": "53.7 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1002.gifWhat is the impedance of the circuit in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "125.7 ohm",
        "b": "297.6 ohm",
        "c": "370.1 ohm",
        "d": "423.3 ohm",
        "answer": "370.1 ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate phase angle in a series RLC circuit when VC = 117 V, VR = 14.5 V, and VL = 3.3 V?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "\u201345.0 degrees",
        "b": "\u201382.7 degrees",
        "c": "\u201390.0 degrees",
        "d": "\u2013172.7 degrees",
        "answer": "\u201382.7 degrees"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement best describes reactance in a series RLC circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Capacitive reactance is always dominant.",
        "b": "Inductive reactance is always dominant.",
        "c": "Resistance is always dominant.",
        "d": "The larger of the two reactances is dominant.",
        "answer": "The larger of the two reactances is dominant."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the band pass (F1 \u2013 F2) of an RLC filter that resonates at 150 kHz and has a coil Q of 30?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "100.0 kHz to 155.0 kHz",
        "b": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz",
        "c": "295.5 kHz to 4500 kHz",
        "d": "149,970 Hz to 150,030 Hz",
        "answer": "147.5 kHz to 152.5 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1010_1.gifWhat is the power factor?\r\n",
        "a": "0.279",
        "b": "0.479",
        "c": "0.679",
        "d": "0.879",
        "answer": "0.879"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1009_1.gif",
        "a": "61.4\u00ba",
        "b": "28.5\u00ba",
        "c": "-28.5\u00ba",
        "d": "-61.4\u00ba",
        "answer": "-28.5\u00ba"
    },
    {
        "question": "What would be the power factor for an RLC circuit that acts inductively?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "+90 degrees leading",
        "b": "one",
        "c": "zero",
        "d": "\u201390 degrees lagging",
        "answer": "zero"
    },
    {
        "question": "Voltage lags current in an RLC circuit when it acts:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "capacitively",
        "b": "resistively",
        "c": "inductively",
        "d": "resonantly",
        "answer": "capacitively"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq13_1008.gifWhat is the bandwidth of the circuit in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "11.6 Hz",
        "b": "275.9 Hz",
        "c": "1.5 kHz",
        "d": "3.2 kHz",
        "answer": "275.9 Hz"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq9_1007_1.gifWhat is the voltage across R1, C1, and L1?\r\n",
        "a": "VR = 156 V, VC = 165 V, VL = 441 V",
        "b": "VR = 178 V, VC = 187 V, VL = 503 V",
        "c": "VR = 219 V, VC = 232 V, VL = 619 V",
        "d": "VR = 260 V, VC = 276 V, VL = 735 V",
        "answer": "VR = 156 V, VC = 165 V, VL = 441 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1007.gifWith the frequency given, the circuit in the given circuit is operating above resonance.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1007_1.gifThe current through the inductor is 5 amps.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1010_1.gifResonance will occur when XC = XL in the circuit below.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1008_1.gifThe resonant frequency fo is 19 kHz.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1003_1u.gifThe impedance is 1177 ohm.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1002.gifThe current lags the voltage in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1006_1.gifThe impedance is 160 ohm.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The greater the selectivity, the wider the bandwidth.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A parallel tuned circuit can be used to couple energy from one circuit to another.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1004_1.gifThe impedance is 9684 ohm.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a series RLC circuit, at above resonance the circuit is more capacitive than it is inductive.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1005_1.gifThe voltage across the inductor is 77.8 volts.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1002.gifIf the given circuit were at resonance, the total current would be at its maximum.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Series LC combinations are used more often in tuned amplifier circuits than are parallel LC combinations.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The quality factor of a parallel circuit at resonance is VC\/VS or VL\/VS.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "When inductive and capacitive reactance are present in the same series circuit, the magnitude of the total reactance is equal to the sum of the magnitudes of the individual reactances.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The quality factor at resonance of a series circuit is VR\/VL.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The less selective a filter is, the steeper the slope of its curves at the cutoff frequencies.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1007.gifIf the given circuit in were operating at resonance, the total current would be maximum.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1007.gifIf the output voltage were taken across the resistor in the given circuit, the circuit would be a band-stop filter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq9_1012_1.gifThis circuit is a high-pass filter.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "By increasing the resistance of a coil you can increase the Q of the coil at resonance.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bandwidth of a filter is the range of frequencies between the half-power frequencies.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq13_1002.gifIf the output voltage were taken from across the resistor in the given circuit, the circuit would be a band-pass filter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a parallel tank is used in series with an output load resistor the filter is a(n) ______ filter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "band-stop",
        "b": "low-pass",
        "c": "bandpass",
        "d": "high-pass",
        "answer": "band-stop"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1007.gifThe phase angle is ______ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "34.5\u00b0",
        "b": "43.3\u00b0",
        "c": "46.7\u00b0",
        "d": "55.5\u00b0",
        "answer": "46.7\u00b0"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ___ of a circuit describes the ability of that circuit to respond to certain frequencies while rejecting all others.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "bandwidth",
        "b": "selectivity",
        "c": "sensitivity",
        "d": "quality factor",
        "answer": "selectivity"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1005.gifThe output voltage is _____ at the resonant frequency in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0 mV",
        "b": "31.4 mV",
        "c": "66.5 mV",
        "d": "380 mV",
        "answer": "66.5 mV"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1009.gifThe output voltage at the resonant frequency is ______ in the given circuit. If a 10 komega.gif load is connected.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "553 mV",
        "b": "5.65 V",
        "c": "6.01 V",
        "d": "6.5 V",
        "answer": "5.65 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1001.gifThe phase angle is ______ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "27.6\u00b0",
        "b": "62.4\u00b0",
        "c": "74.1\u00b0",
        "d": "76.1\u00b0",
        "answer": "27.6\u00b0"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1009.gifThe output voltage at the resonant frequency is _____ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0 V",
        "b": "557 mV",
        "c": "6.08 V",
        "d": "6.5 V",
        "answer": "6.08 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ______ of a circuit describes the ability of that circuit to respond to certain frequencies while rejecting all others.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "bandwidth",
        "b": "selectivity",
        "c": "sensitivity",
        "d": "quality factor",
        "answer": "selectivity"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1007.gifThe total circuit current is _____ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1.52 mA",
        "b": "1.61 mA",
        "c": "2.21 mA",
        "d": "2.71 mA",
        "answer": "2.21 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "At frequencies well above and below the resonant frequency, the series RLC circuit looks ______ and the parallel RLC circuit looks ______.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "like a short, like an open",
        "b": "like an open, like a short",
        "c": "inductive, capacitive",
        "d": "capacitive, inductive",
        "answer": "capacitive, inductive"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1005.gifThe bandwidth is ______ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "179.28 Hz",
        "b": "3.54 kHz",
        "c": "4.44 kHz",
        "d": "15.85 kHz",
        "answer": "3.54 kHz"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq13_1001.gifThe voltage across the inductor is ______ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "6.5 V",
        "b": "12.4 V",
        "c": "14 V",
        "d": "50 V",
        "answer": "50 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a parallel tank circuit is used in series with an output load resistor the filter is ______.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "low-pass",
        "b": "band-stop",
        "c": "band-pass",
        "d": "high-pass",
        "answer": "band-stop"
    },
    {
        "question": "Series resonance happens when _____.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "XC = XC",
        "b": "XL = XC",
        "c": "XL = XB",
        "d": "XT = R",
        "answer": "XL = XC"
    }
]